<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: misc | Securious]]></title>
  <link href="http://xs411.github.io/blog/categories/misc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://xs411.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-22T14:46:31-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://xs411.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[securious]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Securious is Now on Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://xs411.github.io/blog/2013/09/08/securious-is-now-on-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-08T21:14:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://xs411.github.io/blog/2013/09/08/securious-is-now-on-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You may notice a drastic change in the look and feel of the site. We have recently migrated to <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a>.
Octopress is a blog-aware platform that generates static websites based on the
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown">Markdown</a> language. This makes editing posts on any
text editor very easy. A static website is a site that
consists of only HTML, CSS and some JavaScript. The only dynamic aspects of this site are comments and
search. However, search is performed by <a href="http://www.google.com">Google</a> and comments are done in a separate iFrame by <a href="http://disqus.com/">Disqus</a>. This
dramatically reduces the security footprint of the website &ndash; a welcome architecture feature
for a security blog.</p>

<p>More to come soon. Big thanks to <a href="http://twitter.com/coryfoo">@coryfoo</a> for the recommendation to use <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Curious About Security]]></title>
    <link href="http://xs411.github.io/blog/2013/08/16/curious-about-security/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-16T18:16:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://xs411.github.io/blog/2013/08/16/curious-about-security</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Securio.us is a small consulting shop that specializes in web application security testing. Our testing methodology identifies
vulnerabilities covered by the <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Category:OWASP_Top_Ten_Project">OWASP Top 10</a> and the
<a href="http://projects.webappsec.org/w/page/13246978/Threat%20Classification">WASC Threat Classification</a>. Our consultants are
<a href="http://www.giac.org/certification/security-essentials-gsec">GSEC</a> certified. We test running applications and attempt to
subvert security controls by manipulating application inputs. We gather the resulting vulnerabilities that we identify into a
final report and walk through this document to be sure you understand the issues. Verification of findings may be added at an
additional cost. We operate on a wide variety of languages, platforms and technologies. We can test web applications, web
services, and mobile apps on iOS and Android.</p>

<p>We are located in the San Francisco Bay Area in California. If you would like to reach us, please contact us by phone at:
&#52;15.8&#56;9.&#56;815</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
